<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Fahim Montasir Misbah</title>
    <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Fahim Montasir Misbah</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://fahimscirex.github.io/img/blog-banner.webp</url>
      <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/img/blog-banner.webp</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:40:51 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Restoring Windows 10 EFI/GPT Bootloader</title>
      <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/journal/restore-windows-10-efi-bootloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:40:51 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/journal/restore-windows-10-efi-bootloader/</guid>
      <description>Few days ago I installed Archcraft again. The latest update has some cool stuffs, I wanted to try them. As usual both of my bootloader was gone, I use a dual booted system. I&amp;rsquo;ve faced that issue many times and fixed that on my own. But this time it was a litte different, this happened for the first time after switching to UEFI from Legacy. Also it was the first time after I&amp;rsquo;ve started using systemd-boot instead of GRUB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Gtk File Picker</title>
      <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/linux/set-gtk-file-picker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:22:14 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/linux/set-gtk-file-picker/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using Archcraft with bspwm right now. It uses qt applications as default mostly. I don&amp;rsquo;t like the default qt file picker dialog it uses. And couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any good guideline to change the picker. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to write down a workaround I got from @ahmubashshir.
We need some dependencies :
 qt5ct kvantum-qt5 xdg-desktop-portal-gtk  Create a config file under ~/qt5ct/qt5ct.conf with the following content :
[Appearance] standard_dialogs=gtk3 style=kvantum-dark Now set the following environment variable at startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OneDrive Synchronization in Linux</title>
      <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/linux/onedrive-synchronization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 22:15:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/linux/onedrive-synchronization/</guid>
      <description>OneDrive doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any official client in Linux. So after getting a 5TB OneDrive storage I went for two clients
  onedrive-abraunegg: abraunegg&amp;rsquo;s fork of OneDrive CLI client by skilion. Basically it does the synchronization part.
  onedriver : it has a wicked simple GUI. Onedriver will mount your OneDrive storage as a native Linux file system.
  Installation Let&amp;rsquo;s install them first. I&amp;rsquo;m going to install onedriver-git, cause it has some extra GUI functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Your Polybar Panel Icon</title>
      <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/linux/fix-polybar-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 01:53:19 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/linux/fix-polybar-icon/</guid>
      <description>Polybar let&amp;rsquo;s you choose multiple fonts and sizes for your WM panel. So if you&amp;rsquo;re having issues with the size of icons/texts in your panel you can change the size individually. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to the point. How are you supposed to do that?
You&amp;rsquo;ve to define which font you want to use and how you want to customize it&amp;rsquo;s value. So put those values in your Polybar config under [bar/example]. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example config :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Warp on Linux and Get Unlimited Warp Plus Data</title>
      <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/linux/setup-cloudflare-warp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 18:15:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/linux/setup-cloudflare-warp/</guid>
      <description>Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s Warp is a great service to re-route DNS query and bypass blocked website. Though it has clients for Windows, Mac, Android, IOS it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a Warp client for Linux (Cloudflare released a CLI client for Linux systems). Still we can use an unofficial client to get our work done.
WGCF WGCF is an unofficial, cross-platform CLI for Cloudflare Warp. It works with Wireguard. So before installing WGCF make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve installed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capernaum</title>
      <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/journal/capernaum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/journal/capernaum/</guid>
      <description>I can’t remember when the last time I’d watched a movie like Capernaum. But this movie has won my heart, I can say that without any doubt. Capernaum is a name of ancient Israeli city which was condemned to hell by Jesus. In french literature it is used to portray hell, chaos; a large mess that seems impossible to clean. Director Nadine Labaki has taken the word ‘Capernaum’ to signify the lifestyle of a young boy in chaotic, merciless Beirut.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
