<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Polybar on Plugged Into Matrix</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/tags/polybar/</link><description>Recent content in Polybar on Plugged Into Matrix</description><image><url>https://fahimscirex.github.io/47</url><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/47</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 01:53:19 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fahimscirex.github.io/tags/polybar/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How was my IELTS experience and others</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/jrnl/ielts-experience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 17:23:22 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/jrnl/ielts-experience/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Under any circumstances, I&rsquo;m not the person to give IELTS suggestions to anyone, but the least I could do is share my experience and understanding. Also, one of the biggest reasons for posting this everywhere is that I don&rsquo;t want others to fall into the same situation as I did. If they do, at least they can get some direction on what to do afterward.</p>
<p>My actual exam date was 7th April, which I couldn&rsquo;t attend because I was so dumb that I didn&rsquo;t bring my passport with me. As a result, the authorities didn&rsquo;t let me enter the hall. I was about to lose the full fee, which is currently 20,250 BDT. As per IELTS policy, you won&rsquo;t get any refund or be able to reschedule your date if you&rsquo;re absent on the exam date.</p>
<p>The reason I didn&rsquo;t know about all of these things was that I didn&rsquo;t take any IELTS courses or mock tests and didn&rsquo;t look at the IELTS T&amp;C. My knowledge was strictly limited to the question patterns. You may say I wasn&rsquo;t serious about the exam, or else I would&rsquo;ve known about all of these. Well, that wasn&rsquo;t the case, but I won&rsquo;t try to defend myself. After all, it&rsquo;s my fault.</p>
<p>However, I was able to reschedule my exam date by contacting customer care, giving proper reasons, and paying an extra 10% of the whole amount.</p>
<p>Now, getting to the actual IELTS part. As I have said, I didn&rsquo;t take any course or mock test. I had some valid reasons for that. I didn&rsquo;t have enough time to attend any course, and it&rsquo;s a bit tough for me to spend this amount of money on a single exam in a short period.</p>
<p>So, I had to rely on online materials to understand how this IELTS thing has to be done. I prepared for a few days roughly. Now, don&rsquo;t get your hopes high without understanding the whole point. It&rsquo;s not like a few days are always enough to get a good score. Yes, it&rsquo;s possible to get a good score without taking months of preparation if your English skills are already decent enough. Twelve years of schooling is more than enough to make you a decent English user. But if you&rsquo;re not confident enough, you have to do some more work.</p>
<p>By online materials, I meant three specific things: two YouTube channels and a website. That&rsquo;s all it took.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@E2IELTS">E2 IELTS</a> : I watched some of their videos to understand the whole exam pattern. They have short videos on every module, explaining the basics.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@ielts-uponlinelessons7695/">IELTS-up Online lessons</a> : To get ideas and instructions about writing.</li>
<li><a href="https://ielts69.com/">IELTS69</a> : A pretty useful website that has almost everything you need.</li>
</ul>
<p>These three things will cover reading, writing, listening, and a bit of speaking. Speaking is about practicing, so get a speaking partner or talk to yourself. Just make sure people can understand what you&rsquo;re saying. You don&rsquo;t have to be too hard on yourself about it.</p>
<p>Another thing is, IELTS on computer or IELTS on paper? I prefer computer. My typing is fairly good and accurate, and I am comfortable in typing rather than writing. The difference between these two options is about the timing. You&rsquo;ll get ten minutes to check your answers before submitting your writing module on paper-based, while the time is two minutes on the computer. It doesn&rsquo;t matter much, to be honest. You won&rsquo;t need more than two minutes to check your answers on the computer.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all, I guess. Again, I&rsquo;m not the person to give proper suggestions regarding IELTS. You should get an idea from this write-up and take further steps or seek a seek professional&rsquo;s assessment.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Absolute Basics of MPV</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/mpv-basics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 18:48:01 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/mpv-basics/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>For media players there are plenty of options to choose from. But I like to stick with mpv, mostly because it&rsquo;s absolutely minimal and higly configurable. It doesn&rsquo;t have an UI like VLC or Pot Player, but it&rsquo;s very easy to use and you&rsquo;re not bound to anything, write your scripts and configure as you want. If you don&rsquo;t know scripting, mpv-scripts have got you covered with a huge collection of scripts from the community.</p>
<p>Now, when I said it&rsquo;s minimal I actually meant it. Sure, default config works out of the box but you may want to take it a few step further. That&rsquo;s where this guide is going to help you, at least I hope it would.</p>
<h2 id="configuration-file">Configuration File</h2>
<p>The file <em>mpv.conf</em> contains all of the required configuration. The system-wide location for the config file usually is <em>/etc/mpv</em> and user-specific directory is <code>~/.config/mpv/</code>.</p>
<p>Config file looks like this :</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"><span style="display:flex;"><span># Use GPU-accelerated video output by default.
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>vo=gpu
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span># Use quotes for text that can contain spaces:
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>term-status-msg=&#34;Time: ${time-pos}&#34;
</span></span></code></pre></div><h2 id="video">Video</h2>
<p>Here is my current config that handles the video section :</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"><span style="display:flex;"><span>vo=gpu-next
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>gpu-api=vulkan
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>vo-vaapi-scaling=hq
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>hwdec=vaapi
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>hwdec-codecs=all
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>scale=ewa_lanczos
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>scale-blur=0.981251
</span></span></code></pre></div><h3 id="vodriver1driver2"><code>vo=&lt;driver1,driver2,...[,]&gt;</code></h3>
<p>By default the selected video output driver is <em>gpu</em>, as the name suggests it&rsquo;s gpu-accelarated. It&rsquo;s fairly enough, and that&rsquo;s what you should use if you don&rsquo;t want any hassle. But I use <em>gpu-next</em>, which is experimental driver and has bugs. It has almost everything what <em>gpu</em> offers, but it&rsquo;s faster, provides better quality. video drivers can be overridden using the <em>vo</em> flag</p>
<p>Also there are drivers that are only compatible with X11, such as <em>xv</em>, <em>x11</em>, <em>vdpau</em>. Dedicated <em>rpi</em> driver for Raspberry Pi. <em>dmabuf-wayland</em> and <em>wlshm</em> for Wayland etc. Check <a href="https://mpv.io/manual/master/#video-output-drivers">this</a> for all available drivers.</p>
<h3 id="gpu-apitype"><code>gpu-api=&lt;type&gt;</code></h3>
<p><em>gpu-api</em> controls which type of graphics APIs will be accepted. Available options are <em>auto</em>, <em>opengl</em>, <em>vulkan</em>, <em>d3d11</em>. If you have relatively modern hardware you should use <em>vulkan</em>, as it gives better performance but if you face issues you should get back to <em>opengl</em> that&rsquo;s the default.</p>
<h3 id="hwdecapi"><code>hwdec=&lt;api&gt;</code></h3>
<p>Specifies which hardware decoding api should be used, see <a href="https://mpv.io/manual/master/#options-hwdec">this</a> for available options. Hardware decoding is turned off by default, as it requires modern hardware. If you don&rsquo;t want to go through which options is suitable for you, just use <em>yes</em> it will automatically use available decoders. If you explicitly want to specify then use <em>nvdec</em> for NVIDIA GPU&rsquo;s otherwise you should use <em>vaapi</em> for the most cases.</p>
<h3 id="hwdec-codecscodec1codec2all"><code>hwdec-codecs=&lt;codec1,codec2,...|all&gt;</code></h3>
<p>You can specify which codec you would like to use for hardware decoding. The special value <em>all</em> always allows all codecs. You can get the list of allowed codecs by running <code>mpv --vd=help</code>.</p>
<h3 id="scalefilter"><code>scale=&lt;filter&gt;</code></h3>
<p>It is used to upscale the video and it&rsquo;s only available if you&rsquo;re using gpu, gpu-next or libmpv as video output driver. For available filters check <a href="https://mpv.io/manual/master/#options-scale">this</a>. Upscaling isn&rsquo;t really necessary if the video you&rsquo;re playing matches the resolution of your monitor. By setting <em>scale-blur=0.981251</em> imitates <em>ewa_lanczossharp</em> filter, which is currently deprecated.</p>
<h2 id="audio">Audio</h2>
<p>My current config that handles audio output :</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"><span style="display:flex;"><span>ao=pipewire
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>volume=100
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>volume-max=200
</span></span></code></pre></div><h3 id="aodriver1driver2"><code>ao=&lt;driver1,driver2,...[,]&gt;</code></h3>
<p>Usually it isn&rsquo;t necessary to specify audio output drivers, mpv does that fine. Check <a href="https://mpv.io/manual/master/#audio-output-drivers-ao">this</a> for available audio output drivers. I&rsquo;m using <em>pipewire</em> as this is what I use on my system.</p>
<h3 id="volumevalue"><code>volume=&lt;value&gt;</code></h3>
<p>Specify the default volume that will be set when mpv starts up.</p>
<h3 id="volume-max1000-10000"><code>volume-max=&lt;100.0-1000.0&gt;</code></h3>
<p>Set the maximum amplification level in percent (default: 130).</p>
<h2 id="language-priority">Language Priority</h2>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"><span style="display:flex;"><span>alang=en,eng
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>slang=en,eng
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><em>alang</em> refers to audio language and <em>slang</em> refers to subtitle language you can add as much language as you can, mpv will follow that order.</p>
<h2 id="screenshot">Screenshot</h2>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"><span style="display:flex;"><span>screenshot-format=png
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>screenshot-png-compression=1
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>screenshot-directory=&#34;~/Pictures/mpv-screenshots&#34;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>screenshot-template=&#34;%F - [%P]v%#01n&#34;
</span></span></code></pre></div><h3 id="screenshot-formattype"><code>screenshot-format=&lt;type&gt;</code></h3>
<p>Available choices are <em>png</em>, <em>jpg</em>, <em>jpeg</em>, <em>webp</em>, <em>jxl</em>.</p>
<h3 id="screenshot-png-compression0-9"><code>screenshot-png-compression=&lt;0-9&gt;</code></h3>
<p>Set the PNG compression level. Higher means better compression. Too high compression might occupy enough CPU time to interrupt playback. Check <a href="https://mpv.io/manual/master/#screenshot">this</a> for other options dedicated to the formats.</p>
<h3 id="screenshot-directorypath"><code>screenshot-directory=&lt;path&gt;</code></h3>
<p>Set your desired directory as default for screenshots.</p>
<h3 id="screenshot-templatetemplate"><code>screenshot-template=&lt;template&gt;</code></h3>
<p>Specify the filename template used to save screenshots. The template specifies the filename without file extension. Check <a href="https://mpv.io/manual/master/#options-screenshot-template">this</a> for further instruction.</p>
<p><code>%F - [%P]v%#01n</code> this template takes video filename, playback time, number of screenshot and puts together in screenshot filename.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s how the config file looks after adding all of the section together :</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"><span style="display:flex;"><span>## Video
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>vo=gpu-next
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>gpu-api=vulkan
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>vo-vaapi-scaling=hq
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>hwdec=vaapi
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>hwdec-codecs=all
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>scale=ewa_lanczos
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>scale-blur=0.981251
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>## Audio
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>ao=pipewire
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>volume=100
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>volume-max=200
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>## Language Priority
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>alang=en,eng
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>slang=en,eng
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>## Screenshot
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>screenshot-format=png
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>screenshot-png-compression=1
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>screenshot-directory=&#34;~/Pictures/mpv-screenshots&#34;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>screenshot-template=&#34;%F - [%P]v%#01n&#34;
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>This is the absolute basic config that you can start with.</p>
<h2 id="user-scripts">User Scripts</h2>
<p>mpv has support for scripting. Scripts should be put inside <code>~/.config/mpv/scripts</code> directory, mpv will load them while starting up. You&rsquo;ll find a huge collection of scripts created by the community in the <a href="https://github.com/mpv-player/mpv/wiki/User-Scripts">github wiki</a> of mpv.</p>
<h3 id="mpv-script-directoryhttpsnudingithubiompv-script-directory"><a href="https://nudin.github.io/mpv-script-directory/">mpv-script-directory</a></h3>
<p>This webpage indexes various scripts which are searchable and can be filtered to find your desired script easily.</p>
<h3 id="mplughttpsgithubcomnudinmplug"><a href="https://github.com/Nudin/mplug">mplug</a></h3>
<p>mplug is a plugin manager for mpv. Basically it helps you to search, install, uninstall mpv scripts and manage them conveniently.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>My Take on Demolition</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/jrnl/my-take-on-demolition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 23:10:02 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/jrnl/my-take-on-demolition/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I finished watching <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1172049/">Demolition</a> (2015) today starring Jake Gyllenhaal. I had never experienced like this before. Or maybe I did; I just don&rsquo;t remember those moments. I felt connected to the story, to Davis&rsquo;s feelings. It was like I was realizing every moment, and everything happened around it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/demolition.jpg" alt="Jake Gyllenhaal"  />
</p>
<p>Some parts were related to my life or maybe not, it just feels like it is. Sometimes you&rsquo;ll never know what something meant to you until you lose it. For Davis, it was her wife, though he told some people he never loved her wife, but deep inside something was eating him out when she was not around him anymore. He started to notice every small thing happening around himself.</p>
<p>He was struggling to figure out why he thinks he wasn’t in love with her wife. Digging deep inside him, he wanted to look what’s the matter. Tearing apart all memories demolishing his earlier self, he tried to bring out something meaningful.</p>
<p>It seems true that sadness touches you more easily. I should be saying “Melancholy” instead of sadness, I guess. Yes, that’s the word, it belongs here. Human emotions are too complex to understand.</p>
<p>To me, life is about living it. When something stands ahead of you, you don’t stop, continuing the living process is life. And when others join you in that journey, it gets even better, more bearable. To love and to be loved while you live is an amazing thing.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>I&rsquo;m taking part in <a href="https://t.me/+IJgt9FAyBWU4OGFl">The Penguins Club</a> BlogTalk event through this post. #blogtalk #penguinsclub</em></p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Movies That I Don't Want You To Miss Out</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/jrnl/recent-watchlist/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 21:54:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/jrnl/recent-watchlist/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Watched some great movies recently, and I feel like I really should share my thoughts about them with others. I don&rsquo;t want anyone to miss out on these films. They are not listed in any particular order.</p>
<h2 id="prisoners-2013">Prisoners (2013)</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s a crime thriller, Hugh Jackman and Jake Gyllenhaal are in the starring that&rsquo;s quite enough to make me convince watching this movie. And I must say, I enjoyed every second. Actually it&rsquo;s not about prison as the name suggests, it&rsquo;s about abduction of children by serial killer.</p>
<h2 id="deep-water-2022">Deep Water (2022)</h2>
<p>Another one with a fantastic cast, featuring Ben Affleck and Ana de Armas, how can I ignore her? :3 The trailer hooked me in, as I couldn&rsquo;t stop wondering why someone would allow his wife to have affairs when he doesn&rsquo;t approve of it truly. I just had to know the answers. A worth watching psychological thriller.</p>
<h2 id="bullet-train-2022">Bullet Train (2022)</h2>
<p>Probably one of the best of last year, a worth-watching action-comedy. Leading roles played by Brad Pitt, Joey King, Aaron Taylor-Johnson, and Brian Tyree Henry. Adapted from a Japanese novel, the story revolves around hitmen who are trying to complete each of their different missions and everything jumbles up at a point. It&rsquo;s quite humorous and action-packed.</p>
<h2 id="seven-1995">Seven (1995)</h2>
<p>I finally watched it! Don&rsquo;t know what kept me from watching it earlier, it was on my drive for a few years. Definitely it&rsquo;s one of the best crime thrillers of the last century. Directed by David Fincher, a great piece to watch. Two detectives, played by Morgan Freeman and Brad Pitt, start working on a serial killing case. The killer is using the seven deadly sins as a motif, leaving clues for the police, but they just couldn&rsquo;t figure it out. And when they finally do, the story hits even harder.</p>
<h2 id="the-gray-man-2022">The Gray Man (2022)</h2>
<p>When Ryan (literally me) Gosling, Chris Evans, and Ana de Armas are on screen, you know it&rsquo;s going to be something huge. The story follows a former CIA agent who has a bounty placed on him, and he tries to escape while uncovering secret. I won&rsquo;t count it more than a action thriller though, i enjoyed it, that&rsquo;s what matters. Although the ending didn&rsquo;t satisfy me.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>z-lib isn't dead (yet)</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/z-lib-is-not-dead/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 23:21:13 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/z-lib-is-not-dead/</guid><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Disclaimer : This post is not something noob friendly, I won&rsquo;t give explanation to everything. Find out yourself.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You might have heard FBI seized Z-library aka z-lib a week ago. Pretty devastating situation for a lot of people, everyone is mourning over z-lib&rsquo;s death. People are <a href="https://www.dailydot.com/unclick/z-library-tiktok-colleen-hoover/">blaming</a> Coleen Hoover fans on TikTok for this demise (I don&rsquo;t like her writings TBH).</p>
<p>Anyway, there is more to the story. Z-lib isn&rsquo;t actually dead. Their site is still up and running. What FBI did to z-lib is only related to their domains. Technically they have no control over z-lib&rsquo;s backend. So it is still accessible, but it&rsquo;s a bit tricky to access their service right now.</p>
<p>Z-lib started their journey as a mirror of Library Genesis aka libgen which is completely functional right now. Most of their content is from libgen, also they have uploaded additional content over these years.</p>
<p>As I have already said, this post isn&rsquo;t meant to be a beginner-friendly guide about accessing z-lib. I certainly don&rsquo;t want it to be popular again which could lead to another strike.</p>
<p>z-lib is currently accessible from <code>aHR0cHM6Ly9zaW5nbGVsb2dpbi5tZS8K</code> (address is encoded in base64)</p>
<p>Log in there first and you&rsquo;ll get further instructions about accessing z-lib. You can access z-lib through TOR, I2P or Telegram Bot.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Make YouTube Great Again w/ userscripts</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/youtube-userscripts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 09:36:59 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/youtube-userscripts/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>It takes at least three addons to make YouTube bearable for me (e.g. <a href="http://www.mrfdev.com/enhancer-for-youtube">Enhancer for YouTube</a>, <a href="https://www.returnyoutubedislike.com/install">Return YouTube Dislike</a>, <a href="https://sponsor.ajay.app/">SponsorBlock for YouTube</a>, <a href="https://improvedtube.com/">Improve YouTube</a>) which is too much just for a single website.</p>
<p>The easiest solution would be to start using Invidious or Piped instances. They are pretty great, no addons required to remove ads or sponsors or anything. Not a fan of their UI though, it bugs me during watching a video and I don&rsquo;t want to missout liking or disliking videos, commenting, creating a playlist and other basic features that YouTube provides. So Invidious is not the best option out there for me.</p>
<p>My instant thought was to find an addon that combines those three addons and makes me mentally stable lol. But couldn&rsquo;t find any and I don&rsquo;t have the knowledge to create an addon for myself. Then I started looking for userscripts, and found some.</p>
<h2 id="nova-youtube-extensionhttpsgithubcomraingartnova-youtube-extension"><a href="https://github.com/raingart/Nova-YouTube-extension">Nova YouTube Extension</a></h2>
<p>It has lot&rsquo;s of features that Enhancer for YouTube and Improve YouTube provides. The all-in-one userscript!</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://camo.githubusercontent.com/79ed0e850557010693acb5f40497438641f824324f68e8478082576c70ef4a2f/68747470733a2f2f6c68332e676f6f676c6575736572636f6e74656e742e636f6d2f4e554a76357949542d364e555437596942676b4e75386b43554c476b624738594c3358586a4e69425f51335857383772766679594462506a353575325254714a696874585f3934593d773634302d683430302d65333635#center"
         alt="Nova YouTube Extension"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Nova YouTube Extension</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="return-youtube-dislikehttpswwwreturnyoutubedislikecominstall"><a href="https://www.returnyoutubedislike.com/install">Return YouTube Dislike</a></h2>
<p>This one doesn&rsquo;t need any introduction I guess. Install it and it should work.</p>
<h2 id="simple-sponsor-skipperhttpsgreasyforkorgenscripts453320-simple-sponsor-skipper"><a href="https://greasyfork.org/en/scripts/453320-simple-sponsor-skipper">Simple Sponsor Skipper</a></h2>
<p>As the name says it&rsquo;s really simple and works like charm. Beside YouTube it works with Invidious and CloudTube.</p>
<h2 id="installation">Installation</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s pretty easy to install userscripts. Install any userscript manager, for better compatibility you may choose <a href="https://www.tampermonkey.net/">Tampermonkey</a>.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>How did I migrate my user data to another ROM?</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/migrate-data-to-new-rom/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:49:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/migrate-data-to-new-rom/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>While I couldn&rsquo;t get the Migrate app working in my device I found something that worked for me. <a href="https://github.com/VR-25/migrator">Migrator</a> : A backup solution and data migration utility for Android.</p>
<p>Basically it&rsquo;s a collection of some shell scripts that will assist you to copy app, data, permissions and other necessary stuffs and restore them afterwards. It&rsquo;s usable as a Magisk module or as a standalone shell script.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Before changing my ROM I did a backup of user apps by running <code>M -beM</code>. This will copy necessary files to <code>/data/migrator/</code>. So enough internal storage is needed to do a backup.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>To avoid storage issue or to use the backup in another device you may export it to external sd card by running <code>M -e -d /storage/XXXX-XXXX</code>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Note : XXXX-XXXX is a bunch of characters that represents your SD Card.</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>Change your ROM or device, delete partitions or reset the device. Install Migrator module through Magisk or just run the script and import the exported backup by running <code>M -i -d /storage/XXXX-XXXX/migrator_exported</code>. If you didn&rsquo;t exported backups, importing is not needed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Finally run <code>M -re</code> to restore everything.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Note : You&rsquo;ll get more information in the README of Migrator&rsquo;s repo, so follow that.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></description></item><item><title>Host Telegram Userbot on GitHub w/o Any Charge</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/deploy-userbot-with-github-action/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 19:17:55 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/deploy-userbot-with-github-action/</guid><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>13.11.2022, Update : GitHub has removed the repo, will continue removing repo which tries to host bot. This post is useless now.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Most of the Cloud Platform doesn&rsquo;t allow hosting userbot. Your account could get banned if you try to host any or if you&rsquo;re lucky you&rsquo;ll be able to use your bot for a while. Setting up a new account frequently and hosting bot on it is a hell of a work, that&rsquo;s why it&rsquo;s wise to use GitHub Actions.</p>
<p>GitHub Actions&rsquo; Workflows aren&rsquo;t meant to be used as a Cloud Platform (eg. Heroku, Railway) but if it can get your job done then why won&rsquo;t you take the advantage? Moreover, you won&rsquo;t have to pay a single penny.</p>
<p>Before taking you to the procedure there&rsquo;s one thing you should know. <strong>Your bot will restart in every 6 hours</strong>. Cause maximum Action timeout is 360 minutes. Well, Heroku apps also restarts in every 6 hours but the main difference here is, your data won&rsquo;t be stored on GitHub.</p>
<p>For example if you use ytdl to download a video usually it goes into download folder and stays there unless you delete it. But with GitHub Action those downloaded files will be gone when your Actions time is finished. I hope you got me.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll share Action script with support for <a href="https://ultroid.tech">Ultroid</a> and <a href="https://github.com/TG-UserBot/TG-UserBot">TG-Userbot</a>.</p>
<h2 id="requirements">Requirements</h2>
<ul>
<li>GitHub Account</li>
<li>One public repo</li>
<li>One private repo</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="fork-public-repo">Fork Public Repo</h2>
<p>Go to <a href="https://github.com/fahimscirex/userbot-workflow">https://github.com/fahimscirex/userbot-workflow</a> and fork the repo.
You&rsquo;re going to deploy your bot in this repository.
Change the contents of <code>.github/workflows/deploy.yml</code> as per your needs. If you want to use Ultroid then keep <code>ultroid.sh</code> or else replace with <code>tguserbot.sh</code>.</p>
<h2 id="create-a-private-repo">Create a Private Repo</h2>
<p>Forked repo can&rsquo;t be switched to private, so you have to create this on your own. This repo is supposed to contain</p>
<ul>
<li><code>.env</code> (for Ultroid)
or</li>
<li><code>config.ini</code> (for TG-Userbot)</li>
</ul>
<p>Why private? Cause you&rsquo;ll keep your personal data here. You would never like to share your APIs or Sessions with others, right? BTW, I&rsquo;m not going write about what will be in those files. Check their respective documentation to learn more. But I can give a suggestion, you should use Railway to host a Redis server.</p>
<h2 id="add-secrets-in-public-repo">Add Secrets in Public Repo</h2>
<p>As your forked repo is going to stay public or you won&rsquo;t get unlimited Action time, you&rsquo;ve to add some secrets. So that you can access the data of your private repo. Go to <em>https://{your_forked_repo}/settings/secrets/actions</em> to add secrets.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ve to add these following secrets -</p>
<ul>
<li><code>GH_NAME</code> : Your GitHub username.</li>
<li><code>GH_MAIL</code> : Mail that you use to sign into GitHub.</li>
<li><code>CREDS</code> : Link to your private repo but without (https://) eg. github.com/{username}/{private repo}.</li>
<li><code>GH_TOKEN</code> : Go to <a href="https://github.com/settings/tokens">https://github.com/settings/tokens</a> to generate a token. Tick repo, workflow and user and hit generate. Copy the token and add it to the secrets.</li>
<li><code>GH_REPO</code> : Your current repo. <code>username/reponame</code> e.g. fahimscirex/userbot-workflow</li>
<li><code>TZ</code> : Timezone. Findout your timezone and put it in your secret. e.g. Asia/Dhaka.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="deploy-your-bot">Deploy Your Bot</h2>
<p>Our work is done. Now run a workflow and check the logs. If everything goes well your bot will restart in every six hours. You can check loop.txt to know when your bot restarted.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Restoring Windows 10 EFI/GPT Bootloader</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/restore-windows-10-efi-bootloader/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:40:51 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/restore-windows-10-efi-bootloader/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Few days ago I installed Archcraft again. The latest update has some cool stuffs, I wanted to try them. As usual both of my bootloader was gone, I use a dual booted system. I&rsquo;ve faced that issue many times and fixed that on my own. But this time it was a litte different, this happened for the first time after switching to UEFI from Legacy. Also it was the first time after I&rsquo;ve started using systemd-boot instead of GRUB.</p>
<p>So the thing was my /boot partition got deleted, I don&rsquo;t know exactly how that happened. Cause /boot is a separate partition. AFAIK /boot doesn&rsquo;t get deleted during installation. Probably it was because ABIF, that tool formatted /boot partition.</p>
<p>As I didn&rsquo;t have backup of my /boot partition, I was panicked that I would&rsquo;ve to reinstall Windows to restore the Windows Boot Manager. I spend hours searching for a solution to recreate the Windows 10 bootloader, tried everything I got and finally got a really simple solution.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s jump into it.</p>
<h1 id="what-will-you-need-to-restore-windows-boot-manager-on-a-gptuefi-system">What will you need to restore Windows Boot Manager on a GPT/UEFI system?</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p><em><strong>A pendrive with Windows 10 .iso burned on it.</strong></em></p>
<p>I suggest to use the official ISO or something closer to it. Cause customized ISO doesn&rsquo;t work most of the time for this type of work.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em><strong>An ESP partition.</strong></em></p>
<p>EFI System Partitions are in fat32. If you don&rsquo;t have a partition already, create one using diskpart with following commands. If you don&rsquo;t know how to open CMD Prompt then scroll a bit.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell"><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; diskpart
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; <span style="color:#81a1c1;font-weight:bold">select</span> disk <span style="color:#b48ead">0</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; create partition efi size<span style="color:#81a1c1">=</span><span style="color:#b48ead">500</span> 
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; format fs<span style="color:#81a1c1">=</span>fat32 quick label<span style="color:#81a1c1">=</span>SYSTEM
</span></span></code></pre></div></li>
<li>
<p><em><strong>And a brain obviously.</strong></em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="restore-windows-10-bootloader">Restore Windows 10 bootloader</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Boot a Windows installation medium.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Choose your language and click on &lsquo;Repair your computer&rsquo;.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Go to Troubleshoot &gt; Advanced Options &gt; Command Prompt.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We&rsquo;re going to assign a letter to ESP/Boot partition. Let&rsquo;s assume my ESP volume number is 1.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell"><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; diskpart
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; <span style="color:#81a1c1;font-weight:bold">select</span> disk <span style="color:#b48ead">0</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; list volume
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; <span style="color:#81a1c1;font-weight:bold">select</span> volume <span style="color:#b48ead">1</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; assign letter f
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; <span style="color:#81a1c1">exit</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><ol start="5">
<li>We&rsquo;re done with assiging. Now we will use bcdboot.exe to create a new EFI Windows bootloader. Make sure that c:\Windows is mounted.</li>
</ol>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell"><span style="display:flex;"><span>&gt; bcdboot c:<span style="color:#ebcb8b">\W</span>indows /s f: /l en-us /f ALL
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Here :</p>
<p><code>c:\Windows</code> - is where Windows is installed.</p>
<p><code>/s</code> - refers to where you want to save the bootloader.</p>
<p><code>/l</code> - language</p>
<p><code>/f </code>- I&rsquo;ve set ALL to copy everything. If you don&rsquo;t want to copy everything, just the UEFI stuffs then write UEFI instead of ALL.</p>
<p>Now bootloader should be copied from c: drive to f: drive. Run <code>bcdedit</code> to confirm that.</p>
<p>Note : It&rsquo;s better to keep only one ESP. So use bcdboot on a temporary ESP partition and copy files to /boot. So that your systemd-boot stays as it is.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all need to do for restoration. Hit me if goes anything wrong. :3</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Set Gtk File Picker</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/set-gtk-file-picker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:22:14 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/set-gtk-file-picker/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m using Archcraft with bspwm right now. It uses qt applications as default mostly. I don&rsquo;t like the default qt file picker dialog it uses. And couldn&rsquo;t find any good guideline to change the picker. So I&rsquo;m going to write down a workaround I got from <a href="https://github.com/ahmubashshir">@ahmubashshir</a>.</p>
<p>We need some dependencies :</p>
<ul>
<li>qt5ct</li>
<li>kvantum-qt5</li>
<li>xdg-desktop-portal-gtk</li>
</ul>
<p>Create a config file under <code>~/qt5ct/qt5ct.conf</code> with the following content :</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#81a1c1">[</span>Appearance<span style="color:#81a1c1">]</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>standard_dialogs<span style="color:#81a1c1">=</span>gtk3
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>style<span style="color:#81a1c1">=</span>kvantum-dark
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Now set the following environment variable at startup.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#81a1c1">exec</span> QT_QPA_PLATFORMTHEME<span style="color:#81a1c1">=</span>qt5ct
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>As I&rsquo;m using bspwm I&rsquo;ve put that on bspwmrc. You can put that on <code>~/.xprofile</code> or something like that if you&rsquo;re using X11.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all you need to do. If you don&rsquo;t know anything about environment variable, I suggest you to <a href="https://duck.com">duck</a> about that.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>OneDrive Synchronization in Linux</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/onedrive-synchronization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 22:15:05 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/onedrive-synchronization/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>OneDrive doesn&rsquo;t have any official client in Linux. So after getting a 5TB OneDrive storage I went for two clients</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/abraunegg/onedrive/">onedrive-abraunegg</a>: abraunegg&rsquo;s fork of OneDrive CLI client by skilion. Basically it does the synchronization part.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/jstaf/onedriver">onedriver</a> : it has a wicked simple GUI. Onedriver will mount your OneDrive storage as a native Linux file system.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="installation">Installation</h2>
<p>Let&rsquo;s install them first. I&rsquo;m going to install onedriver-git, cause it has some extra GUI functions.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>$ yay -S onedrive-abraunegg onedriver-git
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>For other distribution please check those repo.</p>
<h2 id="authorization">Authorization</h2>
<p><code>onedrive-abraunegg</code> can be run by just entering <code>$ onedrive</code>, it will show a specific link and ask for authorization. I&rsquo;m going to follow that link, complete authorization, copy the URL of that blank authorization page and finally paste it to the terminal.</p>
<p>For <code>onedriver</code> either you can use GUI or terminal. Run <code>$ onedriver -a</code> and Login to OneDrive. Mount the OneDrive storage and enjoy. And we&rsquo;re done with onedriver here, rest of the post is about <code>onedrive</code> or you can say <code>onedrive-abraunegg</code>.</p>
<h2 id="setup">Setup</h2>
<p>We need a config file to use <code>onedrive</code> properly, package comes with a config, we&rsquo;ve to copy that to user config folder.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>$ mkdir -p ~/.config/onedrive/
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>$ cp /usr/share/doc/onedrive/config ~/.config/onedrive/config
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>You may want to edit the config file, so that anything doesn&rsquo;t go wrong. I&rsquo;ll suggest you to change <code>sync_dir</code> to different location and <code>upload_only</code> and <code>no_remote_delete</code> to true. But if you&rsquo;re willing to store your cloud data to your local system you should keep <code>upload_only</code> unchanged.</p>
<p>Now put some files in your sync folder or if you already have data in your cloud simply run <code>$ onedrive --synchronization</code> and your sychronization will start. Also you can run <code>$ onedrive -m</code> it will monitor changes in sync directory and will sync automatically.</p>
<p>If you change  the  filters  (skip_file or skip_dir in your configs) you must execute <code>$onedrive --synchronize --resync</code>.</p>
<h2 id="systemd-intigration">Systemd Intigration</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s convenient to start <code>onedrive</code> as a systemd service.</p>
<p>Enable service as root user</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>$ systemctl <span style="color:#81a1c1">enable</span> --now onedrive
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Or,</p>
<p>Enable as non-root user (recommended)</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>$ systemctl --user <span style="color:#81a1c1">enable</span> --now onedrive
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>To stop the service</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>$ systemctl --user disable --now onedrive
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>If you think you need more detailed instruction for usage check the GitHub <a href="https://github.com/abraunegg/onedrive/blob/master/docs/USAGE.md">repo</a>.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Fix Your Polybar Panel Icon</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/fix-polybar-icon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 01:53:19 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/fix-polybar-icon/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/polybar/polybar">Polybar</a> let&rsquo;s you choose multiple fonts and sizes for your WM panel. So if you&rsquo;re having issues with the size of icons/texts in your panel you can change the size individually. Let&rsquo;s get to the point. How are you supposed to do that?</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ve to define which font you want to use and how you want to customize it&rsquo;s value. So put those values in your Polybar config under <code>[bar/example]</code>. Here&rsquo;s an example config :</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"><span style="display:flex;"><span>[bar/example]
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>; font-N = &lt;fontconfig pattern&gt;;&lt;vertical offset&gt;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>font-0 = &#34;Tamsyn:pixelsize=12;0&#34;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>font-1 = &#34;Roboto:size=11:weight=bold;2&#34;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>font-2 = &#34;Noto Sans:size=11;1&#34;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>font-3 = &#34;Iosevka Nerd Font:size=18;3&#34;
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>If you&rsquo;re wondering what the value after semicolon does. It is used to move the font to the up or to the down. Negative value will move it to the down.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s assume I&rsquo;m having problem with a Spotify module icon in my panel. That icon is way big than others. So i&rsquo;m gonna fix that by changing the icon font size. Usually <a href="https://nerdfonts.com">Nerd Fonts</a> is used in Polybar to get a icon, so I&rsquo;m gonna choose Iosevka Nerd Font. As you can see I&rsquo;ve added that in the config already.</p>
<p>That Spotify module config looks like this :</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"><span style="display:flex;"><span>[module/spotify-icon]
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>inherit = module/apps
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>content = 
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>content-font = 3
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>click-left = env LD_PRELOAD=/usr/lib/spotify-adblock.so spotify %U &amp;
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>All you&rsquo;ve to do is, add the <code>content-font</code> value. Here 3 directs to <code>font-3</code>. So, the Spotify module will inherit values from that example bar config which starts with <code>font-3</code>.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all! I&rsquo;m linking the Polybar wiki <a href="https://github.com/polybar/polybar/wiki/Fonts">here</a>, just in case you might need it. :D</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Setup Warp on Linux and Get Unlimited Warp Plus Data</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/setup-cloudflare-warp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 18:15:05 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/bits/setup-cloudflare-warp/</guid><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><strong>Update : 23/10/2021</strong> &gt; As there&rsquo;s a official CLI out there, I&rsquo;m updating the post with instructions for that too.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cloudflare&rsquo;s Warp is a great service to re-route DNS query and bypass blocked website. <del>Though it has clients for Windows, Mac, Android, IOS it doesn&rsquo;t have a Warp client for Linux. Still we can use an unofficial client to get our work done.</del> It has clients for Windows, Mac, Linux, Android, IOS. You can use it in Linux through the official CLI client or with WGCF.</p>
<h2 id="method-1--warp-desktop-client">Method 1 : WARP Desktop Client</h2>
<p>Head over to <a href="https://pkg.cloudflareclient.com/install">this</a>
page and follow the instructions to setup repository for your distro.</p>
<h3 id="installation">Installation</h3>
<ul>
<li>Ubuntu  : <code>sudo apt install cloudflare-warp</code></li>
<li>RHEL/CentOS : <code>sudo yum install cloudflare-warp</code></li>
<li>Arch    : <code>yay -Syu cloudflare-warp-bin</code></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="register-and-connect">Register and Connect</h3>
<p>You have to register for the first time</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>warp-cli register
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Now connect to WARP</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>warp-cli connect
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Run <code>curl https://www.cloudflare.com/cdn-cgi/trace/</code> if the output shows <code>warp=on</code> you&rsquo;re successfully connected to WARP.</p>
<p>To disconnect from WARP</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>warp-cli disconnect
</span></span></code></pre></div><h3 id="enable-service">Enable Service</h3>
<p>You can enable WARP service if you don&rsquo;t want to enter password after every boot.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>systemctl <span style="color:#81a1c1">enable</span> --now warp-svc
</span></span></code></pre></div><h3 id="always-stay-connected-to-warp">Always Stay Connected to WARP</h3>
<p>You may want to use WARP all the time. To do that run this command.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>warp-cli enable-always-on
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Or else it&rsquo;s not necessary.</p>
<p>To check all available commands run <code>warp-cli -h</code>.</p>
<h2 id="method-2--wgcf">Method 2 : WGCF</h2>
<p><a href="https://github.com/ViRb3/wgcf"><strong>WGCF</strong></a> is an unofficial, cross-platform CLI for Cloudflare Warp. It works with Wireguard. So before installing <strong>WGCF</strong> make sure you&rsquo;ve installed</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><code>wireguard-tools</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>wireguard-dkms</code> (if you&rsquo;re using a Linux Kernel older than 5.6)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>resolvconf</code> (as <a href="https://gitlab.com/fazlerabbi37/">@fazlerabbi</a> informed me that he couldn&rsquo;t find resolvconf preinstalled on some operating systems)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Note : You&rsquo;ve to restart your system if you install wireguard-dkms.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can install pre-compiled binary file from it&rsquo;s <a href="https://github.com/ViRb3/wgcf/releases">releases</a> or you can install it from AUR if you&rsquo;re using Arch derivatives.</p>
<h3 id="install-binary-package">Install binary package</h3>
<p>Download the package you need from release page. Then rename the file <code>wgcf</code>, make it executable and copy it to <code>/bin</code> directory.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>chmod +x wgcf
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>sudo cp wgcf /bin
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Or you can install from AUR if you use Arch</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>yay -S wgcf
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Now we will create a Warp account</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>wgcf register
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>And generate a Wireguard configuration using that account information</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>wgcf generate
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>We&rsquo;ve to connect to Warp using that Wireguard configuration. It&rsquo;d be much easier if you put that configuration file in <code>/etc/wireguard</code></p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sudo cp wgcf-profile.conf /etc/wireguard
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Let&rsquo;s connect now</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>wg-quick up wgcf-profile
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>If you want to disconnect, run</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>wg-quick down wgcf-profile
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Probably you&rsquo;d like to run Warp every time when your system boots. You can do that with help of systemd</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>systemctl <span style="color:#81a1c1">enable</span> --now wireguard@wgcf-profile
</span></span></code></pre></div><h3 id="troubleshoot">Troubleshoot</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;m facing some issue frequently. For some unknown reason Wireguard can&rsquo;t connect through my generated configuration profile multiple times. I&rsquo;ve found a way out to resolve that. If you face the same issue you&rsquo;ve to delete the previous profiles and regenerate new one, except your account profile. To do that you can run this :</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sudo rm -rf wgcf-profile.conf <span style="color:#81a1c1">&amp;&amp;</span> wgcf generate <span style="color:#81a1c1">&amp;&amp;</span> sudo rm -rf /etc/wireguard/wgcf-profile.conf <span style="color:#81a1c1">&amp;&amp;</span> sudo cp wgcf-profile.conf /etc/wireguard
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Now start the service again. If you want, you can set an alias for this or make a bash script for convenient usage.</p>
<h2 id="getting-warp-plus-data-for-free">Getting Warp Plus Data for Free</h2>
<p>There&rsquo;s a python script from <a href="https://github.com/ALIILAPRO/warp-plus-cloudflare">alilapro</a> to get free Warp Plus data. We can use that Warp Plus data in Linux also. But we need to get a Device ID to run that. To do that go to <code>wgcf-account.toml</code> and copy the <code>device id</code>. You can use that ID in alilapro script to get free Warp Plus data.</p>
<h3 id="link-your-warp-account-with-other-device-using-1111">Link your Warp account with other device using 1.1.1.1</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Open 1.1.1.1 app. I&rsquo;m using Android here.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>From hamburger menu go to <code>Account</code> &gt; <code>Key</code>. Copy the key and save it somewhere else we will need this.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Go to <code>Advanced</code> &gt; <code>Diagonistics</code> (optional)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Under <code>Client Configuration</code> you&rsquo;ll see a ID. Copy that and save it. (optional)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Now we&rsquo;ve to put our license key into <code>wgcf-account.toml</code>. Open the toml file, replace the existing license key with yours and update your configuration profile using <code>wgcf update</code> and repeat the previous process.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#d8dee9;background-color:#2e3440;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>wgcf update
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>sudo cp wgcf-profile.conf /etc/wireguard
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Now you can use Device ID which you got from toml file or Configuration ID of your 1.1.1.1 in alilapro script.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Capernaum</title><link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/jrnl/capernaum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 18:43:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/jrnl/capernaum/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I can’t remember when the last time I’d watched a movie like Capernaum. But this movie has won my heart, I can say that without any doubt. Capernaum is a name of ancient Israeli city which was condemned to hell by Jesus. In french literature it is used to portray hell, chaos; a large mess that seems impossible to clean. Director Nadine Labaki has taken the word ‘Capernaum’ to signify the lifestyle of a young boy in chaotic, merciless Beirut.</p>
<p>In recent time more than a million Syrian came to Lebanon as refugee. Capernaum showed an important story of their lifestyle. Zain, an little angry Syrian refugee kid who doesn’t know his birth date nor his parents has any documentation of his existence. He blames his abusive parents for bringing him in to this world, a world full of mess. I was awestruck by his performance. His personal life isn’t much different than the character he played, that’s why he made the overall environment more realistic.</p>
<p>Overall this movie is a debatable one also, it questions human existence. Why people take childs if they can’t ensure a better life for them?</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>