<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Telegram on Fahim Montasir Misbah</title>
    <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/tags/telegram/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Telegram on Fahim Montasir Misbah</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://fahimscirex.github.io/img/blog-banner.webp</url>
      <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/img/blog-banner.webp</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 19:17:55 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fahimscirex.github.io/tags/telegram/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Host Telegram Userbot on GitHub w/o Any Charge</title>
      <link>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/journal/deploy-userbot-with-github-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 19:17:55 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahimscirex.github.io/post/journal/deploy-userbot-with-github-action/</guid>
      <description>Most of the Cloud Platform bans account for hosting userbots. Well, good news for you! You don&amp;#39;t have to worry about getting banned again. Here&amp;#39;s how.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Most of the Cloud Platform doesn&rsquo;t allow hosting userbot. Your account could get banned if you try to host any or if you&rsquo;re lucky you&rsquo;ll be able to use your bot for a while. Setting up a new account frequently and hosting bot on it is a hell of a work, that&rsquo;s why it&rsquo;s wise to use GitHub Actions.</p>
<p>GitHub Actions' Workflows aren&rsquo;t meant to be used as a Cloud Platform (eg. Heroku, Railway) but if it can get your job done then why won&rsquo;t you take the advantage? Moreover, you won&rsquo;t have to pay a single penny.</p>
<p>Before taking you to the procedure there&rsquo;s one thing you should know. <strong>Your bot will restart in every 6 hours</strong>. Cause maximum Action timeout is 360 minutes. Well, Heroku apps also restarts in every 6 hours but the main difference here is, your data won&rsquo;t be stored on GitHub.</p>
<p>For example if you use ytdl to download a video usually it goes into download folder and stays there unless you delete it. But with GitHub Action those downloaded files will be gone when your Actions time is finished. I hope you got me.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll share Action script with support for <a href="https://ultroid.tech">Ultroid</a> and <a href="https://github.com/TG-UserBot/TG-UserBot">TG-Userbot</a>.</p>
<h2 id="requirements">Requirements</h2>
<ul>
<li>GitHub Account</li>
<li>One public repo</li>
<li>One private repo</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="fork-public-repo">Fork Public Repo</h2>
<p>Go to <a href="https://github.com/fahimscirex/userbot-workflow">https://github.com/fahimscirex/userbot-workflow</a> and fork the repo.
You&rsquo;re going to deploy your bot in this repository.
Change the contents of <code>.github/workflows/deploy.yml</code> as per your needs. If you want to use Ultroid then keep <code>ultroid.sh</code> or else replace with <code>tguserbot.sh</code>.</p>
<h2 id="create-a-private-repo">Create a Private Repo</h2>
<p>Forked repo can&rsquo;t be switched to private, so you have to create this on your own. This repo is supposed to contain</p>
<ul>
<li><code>.env</code> (for Ultroid)
or</li>
<li><code>config.ini</code> (for TG-Userbot)</li>
</ul>
<p>Why private? Cause you&rsquo;ll keep your personal data here. You would never like to share your APIs or Sessions with others, right? BTW, I&rsquo;m not going write about what will be in those files. Check their respective documentation to learn more. But I can give a suggestion, you should use Railway to host a Redis server.</p>
<h2 id="add-secrets-in-public-repo">Add Secrets in Public Repo</h2>
<p>As your forked repo is going to stay public or you won&rsquo;t get unlimited Action time, you&rsquo;ve to add some secrets. So that you can access the data of your private repo. Go to <em>https://{your_forked_repo}/settings/secrets/actions</em> to add secrets.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ve to add these following secrets -</p>
<ul>
<li><code>GH_NAME</code> : Your GitHub username.</li>
<li><code>GH_MAIL</code> : Mail that you use to sign into GitHub.</li>
<li><code>CREDS</code> : Link to your private repo but without (https://) eg. github.com/{username}/{private repo}.</li>
<li><code>GH_TOKEN</code> : Go to <a href="https://github.com/settings/tokens">https://github.com/settings/tokens</a> to generate a token. Tick repo, workflow and user and hit generate. Copy the token and add it to the secrets.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="deploy-your-bot">Deploy Your Bot</h2>
<p>Our work is done. Now run a workflow and check the logs. If everything goes well your bot will restart in every six hours. You can check loop.txt to know when your bot restarted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
